vesselfinder.com 2019-12-06

# Privacy policy - VesselFinder

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) sets out how VesselFinder uses and protects any information that you give VesselFinder.com website, our mobile applicatiopns, Premium services or other information provided as part of the VesselFinder services (collectively “VesselFinder” or the “Service”) when you use them.

VesselFinder is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using VesselFinder, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

If you have any hesitation about providing information to us and/or having your information displayed on the VesselFinder or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy, you should not become a member of the VesselFinder Services.

## What we collect?

Your successful registration and membership depend on providing the following information:  
\- name  
\- email addres  
\- password  
Without this minimal amount of information, you cannot create a VesselFinder account. Like other passwords, you should choose one that is known only by you. 

## What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you by email for market research purposes. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Your password is protected by encryption so that only you have access to it.

## How we use cookies?

Like most websites, we use cookies and web log files to better understand site usage and improve our services.

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how users use our Service. Google Analytics cookies do not provide VesselFinder with any personally identifiable information. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes. 

Click [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) to learn more about Google Analytics and your privacy. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics when using our web-based products, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better Service, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## Local storage

In addition to cookies, we are utilizing browser local storage technology to store your preferences and make your user experience more consistent. Local storage is a persistent type of storage, that provides similar functionality to cookies, but its contents are not transmitted across the Internet, like cookies are.

Like cookies, you can control how local storage works on your browser settings on a global or website specific manner. Disabling the local storage functionality on your browser will result in loss of functionality of the map and other features of the website.

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## Third parties

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties, except as described in this policy, unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

We may use third party service providers or online payment processing vendors to provide services in connection with our Service and to facilitate services we provide to you. As a result, we may disclose personally identifiable information collected from our website to such third party service providers for the sole purpose of allowing them to perform the Outsourced Services.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of the Service to third parties for purposes that we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on VesselFInder.

## Social Media Features

The VesselFinder website uses social media features (“Social Features”) provided by companies such as Facebook, Twitter and Google+ which help you to share web content directly from web pages to the social media platforms. Users are advised before using Social Features that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external Social Features that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use Social Features wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. VesselFinder nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.

## Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information:

  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by emailing us at [info@vesselfinder.com](mailto:info@vesselfinder.com)

We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete please email us as soon as possible at info@vesselfinder.com. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

VesselFinder may need to update this Policy to keep pace with changes in the Service and laws applicable to us and you. We will, however, always maintain our commitment to respect your privacy.

We will post any revisions to this Policy, therefore we recommend that you periodically check this page to stay informed of any changes.

We will ask for your consent to such changes if required by applicable law; in other cases, please note that your continuation of your VesselFinder Service account after any change means that you agree with, and consent to be bound by, the new Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any changes in this Policy and do not wish your information to be subject to the revised Policy, you will need to close your account before the new Policy becomes effective.

## How do I delete my Membership account?

If you would like to delete your Membership account, please send us an email from the email address that is associated with your Membership account at [info@vesselfinder.com](mailto:info@vesselfinder.com).  
You should be aware that it may not be technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us from our servers. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your personal identifiable information may exist in a non-erasable form that may be difficult or impossible for us to locate.

In addition, we have the right to delete any account at any time if required to do so by process of law, or if necessary in order to investigate fraud, a violation of our Terms of Use or in connection with any harm being caused to a third party or their rights.

## How to Contact us?

VesselFinder welcomes your feedback regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have questions, comments or concerns about this Policy, please contact us by submitting a request here.
